*  

* Search  

[

](https://www.rockford.edu/)

 Mobile Navigation

Privacy Policy Agreement
========================

[Rockford.edu](https://www.rockford.edu/ "Go to Rockford University.") / Privacy Policy Agreement

Privacy Policy Agreement
========================

Thank you for visiting Rockford University’s (“RU’s”) website(s) and service(s).  Your privacy is important to us.  To better protect your privacy, we’ve developed this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used within our sites and services.  Please read on for more details about our privacy policy.

This Privacy Policy Agreement shall apply to all information collected by Rockford University through the use of its website(s). Through the use of [https://www.rockford.edu](https://www.rockford.edu/) you are herein consenting to the following data procedures expressed within this agreement.

#### **Collection of Information**

This website collects various types of information, such as:

* Voluntarily provided information which may include your name, address, email address, billing and / or credit card information, etc., which may be used when you purchase products and or services, give gifts and/or services and to deliver the services you have requested.
* Information automatically collected when visiting our website, which may include cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs.

With the exception of the information automatically collected as described above, this site only collects personal information that you knowingly and willingly provide by way of surveys, completed membership forms, and emails. It is the intent of this site to use personal information only for the purpose for which it was requested and for any additional uses specifically provided on this site.

Rockford University may have the occasion to collect anonymous demographic information, such as age and gender at a later time. We may also gather information about the type of browser you are using, IP address or type of operating system to assist us in providing and maintaining superior quality service.

It is highly recommended and suggested that you review the privacy policies and statements of any website you choose to use or frequent as a means to better understand the way in which other websites garner, make use of and share information collected.

#### **Use of Information Collected**

Rockford University may collect and may make use of personal information provided through this website to assist in the operation of our website and to ensure delivery of the services you need and request. At times, we may find it necessary to use personally identifiable information as a means to keep you informed of other possible products and/or services that may be available to you from [https://www.rockford.edu](https://www.rockford.edu/) . Rockford University may also be in contact with you with regards to completing surveys and/or research questionnaires related to your opinion of current or potential future services that may be offered.

Rockford University may deem it necessary to follow websites and/or pages that our users may frequent in an effort to glean what types of services and/or products may be the most popular to customers or the general public.

#### Cookies

Cookies are messages passed from a website to and stored in an individual’s web browser. Each time the individual visits the same website, the information from the cookie is passed back to the server. Cookies are generally used with the goal of being able to identify unique and/or repeat visitors to a website. Rockford University and third parties acting on behalf of the university, may store and read information from a cookie that the University has placed in an individual’s web browser.

#### **Disclosure to Third Parties**

Rockford University does not sell, rent, give away or lease any of the information collected through its website to any identifiable information regarding users of this website to third parties other than agents and contractors of Rockford University.  Agents and contractors of Rockford University who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this privacy policy by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Rockford University.

Rockford University may disclose your personal information collected through its website to a third party if it believes in good faith that such action is deemed necessary or is required to:

* Comply with the law;
* Enforce or apply the terms of any of our user agreements;
* Maintain, safeguard and/or preserve all the rights and/or property of Rockford University; and
* Perform under demanding conditions in an effort to safeguard the personal safety of users of [https://www.rockford.edu](https://www.rockford.edu/) and/or the general public.

#### Forms

In order to conduct regular business such as accepting admissions applications, event registrations, donations or taking surveys, we may require an individual to enter various information into forms on a website. This data may include identifying information (PII) that is subject to laws including, but not limited to, the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) or the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).

#### **Links to Other Web Sites**

Our website does contain links to affiliate and other websites. Rockford University does not claim nor accept responsibility for any privacy policies, practices and/or procedures of other such websites.

Therefore, we encourage all users and visitors to be aware when they leave our website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. The aforementioned Privacy Policy Agreement applies only and solely to the information collected by our website.

#### **Security**

Rockford University has put into place physical, procedural and technical security with respect to our offices and information storage facilities to help prevent any loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or modification of the user’s personal information collected online.

Rockford University also uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) for authentication and private communications in an effort to build users’ trust and confidence in the internet and website use by providing simple and secure access and communication of credit card and personal information.

#### Opting out

Individuals have the option of disabling or not accepting cookies by changing preferences in their browser. Portions of the University’s website will function normally with cookies disabled, but portions of the website requiring a login (e.g. accessing the university portal.) will be unavailable.

#### **Changes to Privacy Policy Agreement**

Rockford University reserves the right to update and/or change the terms of its privacy policy, and as such we will post those change to our website homepage at [https://www.rockford.edu](https://www.rockford.edu/), so that our users and/or visitors are always aware of the type of information we collect, how it will be used, and under what circumstances, if any, we may disclose such information.

#### **Acceptance of Terms**

Through the use of this website, you are hereby accepting the terms and conditions stipulated within the aforementioned Privacy Policy Agreement. If you are not in agreement with our terms and conditions, then you should refrain from further use of our sites. In addition, your continued use of our website following the posting of any updates or changes to our terms and conditions shall mean that you are in agreement and acceptance of such changes.

#### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding the Privacy Policy Agreement related to our website, please feel free to contact us at the following email, telephone number or mailing address.

Email: gwallace@rockford.edu  
Telephone Number: 815-226-4000

Mailing Address:  
Rockford University  
5050 E State St  
Rockford, Illinois 61108

03/01/2018

ROCKFORD UNIVERSITY

5050 East State Street  
Rockford IL 61108

 815.226.4000

Copyright © 2024 Rockford University, all rights reserved

* [
    
    ](https://www.snapchat.com/add/rockford.u "Snapchat")
* [
    
    ](http://rockford.meritpages.com/ "Merit")
